<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Four Sore Eyes</title>
    <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Four Sore Eyes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://BarryElderwine.github.io/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/2025/2025-tester/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/2025/2025-tester/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing 4se in 2025&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Balance Between Discovery and Generativity</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/eyerubs/the-balance-between-discovery-and-generativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/eyerubs/the-balance-between-discovery-and-generativity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think it may the case that the vastness, and rapid rate of movement of information made available by the internet has created the illusion that access to personally integrable knowledge is easier than it must actually be. Discovery is seductive. The immediacy of access to answers to every question that finds the attention offers the feeling of accomplishment of understanding. But this can&amp;rsquo;t be the case. Our brains don&amp;rsquo;t process  information at this rate and if one doesn&amp;rsquo;t give the mind, not only the time,  but also the appropriate framing of information, then this information is as fleeting in the mind as the chemical messengers that mediate the felt connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Technology</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/eyerubs/human-focused-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/eyerubs/human-focused-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very curious about the purpose of technology. Specifically my intuitions, based of course on my value driven biases, lead me to believe that all technology should or at least could be evaluated based on its ability to enhance some aspect of humanity and the trade-offs. I think this is supported by the fact that technology, by definition, is always a product of human innovation. This notion however may not hold true with the advent of Artificial Intelligence.
Some thoughts I want to explore in this regard:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
