<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Four Sore Eyes</title>
    <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Four Sore Eyes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://BarryElderwine.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Balance Between Discovery and Generativity</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/eyerubs/the-balance-between-discovery-and-generativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/eyerubs/the-balance-between-discovery-and-generativity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think it may the case that the vastness, and rapid rate of movement of information made available by the internet has created the illusion that access to personally integrable knowledge is easier than it must actually be. Discovery is seductive. The immediacy of access to answers to every question that finds the attention offers the feeling of accomplishment of understanding. But this can&amp;rsquo;t be the case. Our brains don&amp;rsquo;t process  information at this rate and if one doesn&amp;rsquo;t give the mind, not only the time,  but also the appropriate framing of information, then this information is as fleeting in the mind as the chemical messengers that mediate the felt connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is there a bridge?</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/eyerubs/is-there-a-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/eyerubs/is-there-a-bridge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found the video &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rEXymLAqqIs&#34;&gt;Why I Converted to Christianity - Ayaan Hirsi Ali&lt;/a&gt; to be oddly reassuring. Alex O&amp;rsquo;Conner does a very nice job of revealing the both the reason and emotion behind his Ayaan&amp;rsquo;s, views, behavior and the values that underly them. This approach to discussion is nearly all but lost in everyday discourse nowadays.  I&amp;rsquo;ve suggested this video to some friends and,  in explaining to them why I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth the time and attention, they each wanted to argue against the reasoning of Ayaan solely based on my representation of her perspectives. This of course underscores the very issue I&amp;rsquo;m trying to raise. It appears the starting point of any discussion now is almost a strike first posture, coming from either side, feeling the need change the mind of the other with &amp;ldquo;common sense&amp;rdquo; reasoning. So why did I find this discussion between Alex and Ayaan so reassuring in spite of the fact that Ayaan seems to me to be so clearly misguided? I do believe that her perspectives are emotionally honest. This somewhat quells my anxiety that comes from my own lack of empathy for those who, to me, feel like they are intentionally being discompassionate and intellectually dishonest. It seems clear that Ayaan is at her core is a compassionate person. So a reasonable explanation for her support for, what I believe are, irrational and unkind perspectives is that her history and experience have put her in a place to receive bad information and develop bias blinded viewpoints with this information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Technology</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/eyerubs/human-focused-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/eyerubs/human-focused-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very curious about the purpose of technology. Specifically my intuitions, based of course on my value driven biases, lead me to believe that all technology should or at least could be evaluated based on its ability to enhance some aspect of humanity and the trade-offs. I think this is supported by the fact that technology, by definition, is always a product of human innovation. This notion however may not hold true with the advent of Artificial Intelligence.
Some thoughts I want to explore in this regard:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Condecision</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/condecision/condecision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/condecision/condecision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Condecision&lt;/strong&gt;: A state where decision making is impeded for an awareness that whatever decision is made the consequences are likely to have a net negative outcome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emplosion</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/condecision/emplosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/condecision/emplosion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;condecion
&lt;strong&gt;Emplosion&lt;/strong&gt;: An occurrence when ones empathic sensibilities contribute  to a state of condecision to the point of emotional, cognitive and behavioral collapse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Emplosion</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/condecision/nuclear-emplosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/condecision/nuclear-emplosion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuclear Emplosion&lt;/strong&gt; A special case of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;emplosion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; when ones empathic sensibilities are spread across 2 or more others whose needs are in conflict each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Made with Natural and Artificial Flavors: Consciousness Part 1 of ...</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/2024/240219-consciousness---made-with-natural-and-artificial-flavors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/2024/240219-consciousness---made-with-natural-and-artificial-flavors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;willful-hedging&#34;&gt;Willful Hedging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell anymore what the trends are in pop-sci-culture with the way we are fed content via the machines. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a whole lot of &amp;ldquo;free will&amp;rdquo; pushed into my online notice in recent weeks. Much of this content is related to the proposition of purposelessness that Robert Sapolsky has made with his book Determined. I did listen to this Audible book a couple months back, and presumably the machines are well aware of that, and as such are willing this related content in my direction. One of these pieces, the greatest grabber of my interest but turned out to be disappointingly  unrevealing, was a podcasted debate between Robert Sapolsky and Daniel Dennett. Daniel Dennett is the most familiar to me adherent of compatibilism, that  is the contention that free will is not incompatible with a determinism.  Dennett&amp;rsquo;s perspective, (my possibly inaccurate interpretation) is that we do in fact have free will, if we constrain the boundaries of an individual&amp;rsquo;s decision making  to only the psychological variables relevant to the context of the situation that demands a conscious decision. At least that&amp;rsquo;s the best argument I can make based on my understanding of his. And I do want to find a good argument for the compatibility of free will in a deterministic framework of human behavior. A core premise, or assumption, of this point of view is  that conscious decisions directly influence behavior. And this is a hard case to make, particularly since we can&amp;rsquo;t find a good scientific, much less conversational baseline to start to flesh out what consciousness is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write out in the open</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/2024/240213-write-out-in-the-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/2024/240213-write-out-in-the-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;reasoning-a-site-four-sore-eyes&#34;&gt;Reasoning &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;A Site Four Sore Eyes&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is  place where I can publish my ideas for the audience of me. I have an ever growing number of thixotropic reasons for setting up this platform.  Probably the greatest overarching argument is to give me a place where I can air out my most persistent ruminations. This, in my fuzzy uncheckable logic, might - just might - provide some time and virtual space between my, in-this-moment thoughts, and my many-later-moments reconsiderations, allowing me to take them in with fresher, or simply differently focused eyes. In support of that objective I hope this platform will also allow me to write and publish more freely, with the only critic I might choose to answer to being that one (or small set) that resides in my mind, wherever that lives inside of me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
