<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Four Sore Eyes</title>
    <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Four Sore Eyes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/testing-new-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/testing-new-workflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is simply a test of a new workflow&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Made with Natural and Artificial Flavors: Consciousness Part 1 of ...</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/2024/240219-consciousness---made-with-natural-and-artificial-flavors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/2024/240219-consciousness---made-with-natural-and-artificial-flavors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;willful-hedging&#34;&gt;Willful Hedging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell anymore what the trends are in pop-sci-culture with the way we are fed content via the machines. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a whole lot of &amp;ldquo;free will&amp;rdquo; pushed into my online notice in recent weeks. Much of this content is related to the proposition of purposelessness that Robert Sapolsky has made with his book Determined. I did listen to this Audible book a couple months back, and presumably the machines are well aware of that, and as such are willing this related content in my direction. One of these pieces, the greatest grabber of my interest but turned out to be disappointingly  unrevealing, was a podcasted debate between Robert Sapolsky and Daniel Dennett. Daniel Dennett is the most familiar to me adherent of compatibilism, that  is the contention that free will is not incompatible with a determinism.  Dennett&amp;rsquo;s perspective, (my possibly inaccurate interpretation) is that we do in fact have free will, if we constrain the boundaries of an individual&amp;rsquo;s decision making  to only the psychological variables relevant to the context of the situation that demands a conscious decision. At least that&amp;rsquo;s the best argument I can make based on my understanding of his. And I do want to find a good argument for the compatibility of free will in a deterministic framework of human behavior. A core premise, or assumption, of this point of view is  that conscious decisions directly influence behavior. And this is a hard case to make, particularly since we can&amp;rsquo;t find a good scientific, much less conversational baseline to start to flesh out what consciousness is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write out in the open</title>
      <link>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/2024/240213-write-out-in-the-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://BarryElderwine.github.io/posts/2024/240213-write-out-in-the-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;reasoning-a-site-four-sore-eyes&#34;&gt;Reasoning &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;A Site Four Sore Eyes&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is  place where I can publish my ideas for the audience of me. I have an ever growing number of thixotropic reasons for setting up this platform.  Probably the greatest overarching argument is to give me a place where I can air out my most persistent ruminations. This, in my fuzzy uncheckable logic, might - just might - provide some time and virtual space between my, in-this-moment thoughts, and my many-later-moments reconsiderations, allowing me to take them in with fresher, or simply differently focused eyes. In support of that objective I hope this platform will also allow me to write and publish more freely, with the only critic I might choose to answer to being that one (or small set) that resides in my mind, wherever that lives inside of me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
